Claire Standley (she/her): So thank you so much i'm truly delighted to be able to welcome today, Dr Amadou Traore
Claire Standley (elle) : Merci beaucoup, je suis très heureuse de pouvoir accueillir aujourd'hui le Dr Amadou Traore,
Claire Standley (she/her): And longtime colleague and collaborator and a public health emergency management experts will be talking to us about his experiences and implementing incident management systems in various phases, but specifically in in Guinea so.
Claire Standley (elle) : collègue et collaborateur de longue date, expert en gestion des urgences de santé publique, qui nous parlera de ses expériences et de la mise en œuvre des systèmes de gestion des incidents dans différentes phases, mais plus particulièrement en Guinée.
Claire Standley (she/her): Amadou, thank you so much for being here. To get us started, could you please briefly describe your background and training in public health emergency management.
Claire Standley (elle) : Amadou, merci beaucoup d'être ici. Pour commencer, pourriez-vous décrire brièvement votre parcours et votre formation en matière de gestion des urgences de santé publique.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Thank you it's a pleasure to be here to take part in this session and, as you said, my name is Amadou Traore, I am a bi-national from Guinea and also Britain.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Merci, c'est un plaisir d'être ici et de participer à cette session. Comme vous l'avez dit, mon nom est Amadou Traore, je suis un binational de Guinée et de Grande-Bretagne.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: My degree is in medicine and from the University of Gamal in Guinea, I also have masters' degrees in public health studies and biomedical science from the UK.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Je suis diplômé en médecine et je viens de l'Université de Gamal en Guinée, j'ai également des masters en études de santé publique et en sciences biomédicales du Royaume-Uni.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: And I am a certified FETP Frontline fellow and also, I have attended an emergency management program fellow in fellowship in in the US in Atlanta.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Et je suis certifié FETP première ligne et j'ai également participé à un programme de gestion des urgences aux États-Unis à Atlanta.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: And so I have been mostly I mean, most recently involved in public health emergency management capacity in Guinea.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : J'ai donc été plus récemment impliqué dans la capacité de gestion des urgences de santé publique en Guinée.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: So I will be pretty much happy to talk to you about that, because my experience is actually span of IHR core capacity building and the GHSA.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Je serai donc très heureux de vous parler de cela, car mon expérience s'étend en fait sur le renforcement des capacités de base du IHR et de la GHSA,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: and in terms of preparedness emergency response operations linking public health and security authorities, also medical countermeasures and.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : et en termes de préparation, les opérations de réponse d'urgence reliant les autorités de santé publique et de sécurité, ainsi que les contre-mesures médicales,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: personnel deployment and risk communication, so I also assume some coordination rules in terms of public public health risk assessment, using, for example, WHO VRAM
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : le déploiement du personnel et la communication des risques, donc je suppose également certaines règles de coordination en termes d'évaluation des risques pour la santé publique, à l'aide, par exemple, du VRAM de l'OMS,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: vulnerability and risk assessment mapping, the strategic tool for the assessment of risk and also the CDC.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : cartographie d'évaluation de la vulnérabilité et des risques, l'outil stratégique pour l'évaluation des risques ainsi que le CDC
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: THIRA, which is the threat and hazard identification and risk assessment so also involved in the.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : THIRA. Il permet l'identification des menaces et des dangers et l'évaluation des risques. Il est donc également impliqué dans
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Management of some exercise program especially tabletop exercise real full scale simulation exercise that both national and regional level, so this is really a brief, probably seems to be a bit long but to give you a good.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : la gestion de certains programmes d'exercices, en particulier les exercices sur table et les exercices de simulation à grande échelle, tant au niveau national que régional, ce n'est donc qu'un bref résumé, qui peut sembler un peu long, mais qui vous donne un bon
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Exposure to the scope of my activities, thank you.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : exposé de l'étendue de mes activités, merci.
Claire Standley (she/her): Well, I think it just reflects the the depth of your experience in this field, so thank you so much for providing that overview.
Claire Standley (elle) : Eh bien, je pense que cela reflète la profondeur de votre expérience dans ce domaine, donc merci beaucoup d'avoir fourni cet aperçu.
Claire Standley (she/her): So so based on your experiences, as you say, across different settings, what are the benefits the practical benefits of using a system like IMS to to coordinate response.
Claire Standley (elle) : Sur la base de votre expérience, comme vous le dites, dans différents contextes, quels sont les avantages pratiques de l'utilisation d'un système comme l'IMS pour coordonner les interventions ?
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: hey um.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Et bien,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Let me just maybe jog my memory back to the Ebola virus disease outbreak in Guinea let's say in West Africa in 2014 and 16.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : permettez-moi de me remémorer l'épidémie de la maladie du virus Ebola en Guinée, disons en Afrique de l'Ouest, en 2014 et 2016.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: So this was a large outbreak and that affected the mostly three countries, including Guinea, Sierra Leone and Liberia, in terms of the management of that emergency there were a lot of.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : C'était donc une grande épidémie qui a touché principalement trois pays, comprenant la Guinée, la Sierra Leone et le Liberia et en termes de gestion de l'urgence il y a eu beaucoup à faire.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Actually, his heels in terms of.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : En réalité, ses points forts en termes de
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: The coordination and also the communication, however, with the experience of CDC and using IMS in in in in in managing some other event.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : la coordination et aussi de la communication, également, avec l'expérience du CDC et l'utilisation de l'IMS dans la gestion d'un autre événement.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: I think that experience was leveraging Guinea and help actually manage very well the outbreak in terms of the coordination and the communication.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Je pense que cette expérience a servi de levier à la Guinée et a permis de très bien gérer l'épidémie en termes de coordination et de communication.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: So definitely some of these advantages would definitely be effective management in terms of coordination and you know communication.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Donc certains de ces avantages seraient certainement une gestion efficace en termes de coordination et de communication.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Additionally, we also can using the IMS achieve in effective use of scarce resources, especially you know for poor settings.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : En outre, nous pouvons également utiliser l'IMS pour une utilisation efficace des ressources limitées, en particulier dans les milieux pauvres.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: And also, it allows you know common operating pictures and manageable span of control, whereas we have one single person not responsible for no more than seven people.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Ceci permet entre autre d'obtenir des images opérationnelles communes et une étendue de contrôle gérable, alors que nous avons une seule personne responsable de sept personnes au maximum.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: And, which is a it is really some of the main advantages that we've seen in Guinea, and it has resulted in a in a good outcome for the management team, or just in general.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Cela constitue réellement l'un des principaux avantages que nous avons observé en Guinée, ce qui s'est traduit par un bon résultat pour l'équipe de gestion ou en général.
Claire Standley (she/her): Thank you yeah I think those those concrete examples are very helpful.
Claire Standley (elle) : Merci, je pense que ces exemples concrets sont très utiles.
Claire Standley (she/her): And so, so going into that a bit more deeply what are some of the challenges, then of implementing a system, you know I think if it was easy we'd see them all over the place, but but, of course, there must be some difficulties or challenges that we need to be overcome.
Claire Standley (elle) : Pour aller un peu plus loin, quels sont les défis de la mise en œuvre d'un système ? Je pense que si c'était facile, on en verrait partout, mais bien sûr, il doit y avoir des difficultés ou des défis à surmonter.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Yes, certainly there are challenges, and you know as for every new system that you want to implement in your countries.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Oui, il y a certainement des défis, mais vous savez comme pour chaque nouveau système que vous souhaitez mettre en œuvre dans vos pays.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: I mean, first of all, you will face some difficulties in terms of implementing.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Tout d'abord, vous serez confrontés à certaines difficultés en termes de mise en œuvre,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: I mean, because the leadership the management will be not welcoming at first because it's a new system that they are not used to it they have
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : car les dirigeants et la direction ne seront pas très accueillants au début, puisque c'est un nouveau système auquel ils ne sont pas habitués. Ils ont
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Probably other experiences, they want to carry on using those experiences.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : probablement d'autres expériences, et souhaitent continuer à les utiliser.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: So the first time, when we started implementing IMS people said Oh, this is a new structure, it would be like a parallel system, how can we really ensure that we achieve this.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Ainsi, la première fois, lorsque nous avons commencé à mettre en œuvre l'IMS, les personnes y ont vu une nouvelle structure, comme un système parallèle. Ils se demandaient comment réellement être sûrs de réaliser
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: This principle of IMS and EOC in a broader sense, so one of the the the advice that I gave coming freshly from Atlanta was, we will not be.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : ce principe de l'IMS et de l'EOC dans un sens plus large. L'un des conseils que j'ai donné en revenant d'Atlanta était que
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Using the system as such as it is used in the US, but we'll add that into our own context, so I use that.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : nous n'utiliserons pas le système tel qu'il est utilisé aux États-Unis, mais nous l'ajouterons dans notre propre contexte. Donc j'ai utilisé
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: expression to try and convince the leadership at the time to accept using it, so instead of creating new structure in terms of the EOC and also the implementation of the IMS.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : cette expression pour essayer de convaincre les dirigeants de l'époque d'accepter de l'utiliser. Ainsi au lieu de créer une nouvelle structure en termes d'EOC et également de mise en œuvre de l'IMS,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: I say let's assign the functions of the EOC and the IMS to staff already on the payroll with the government.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : je leur ai dit que nous devions attribuer les fonctions de l'EOC et de l'IMS au personnel déjà rémunéré par le gouvernement.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: So that's one of the challenges that we had the opposition from the leadership, and the second challenge is also in terms of resources to,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : C'est donc l'un des défis que nous avons dû relever en raison de l'opposition des dirigeants. Et le deuxième défi est également en termes de ressources,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Especially financial resources to train staff, and you know not many people are trained in terms of using IMS so every single time you want to prevent IMS we face people basically by having difficulties in immersing into the depth of this this tool.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : en particulier les ressources financières pour former le personnel. Vous savez, peu de personnes sont formées à l'utilisation de l'IMS, donc chaque fois que vous souhaitez promouvoir l'IMS, nous sommes confrontés à des personnes qui ont des difficultés à s'immerger dans le fonctionnement de cet outil.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: yeah and, yes, so the adaptation to Guinea was quite a good experience, and I think some countries, you know are struggling.
Dr Amadou Traore, de la Sierra Leone : Certes, l'adaptation en Guinée a été une bonne expérience, mais je pense que certains pays ont des difficultés,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Because when you're recruiting new staff, you have to think about you know the funder resources to pay them, whereas in Guinea.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : car lorsque vous recrutez du nouveau personnel, vous devez penser aux ressources financières pour les payer, alors qu'en Guinée,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: You know why it is working perfectly right now in the district is because we use the staff already there and who actually just performing these functions of the IMS in in in the district.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : si cela fonctionne parfaitement à l'heure actuelle dans le district, c'est précisément grâce au fait que nous utilisons le personnel déjà présent et qui remplit les fonctions de l'IMS dans le district.
Claire Standley (she/her): yeah well, and you know I think you mentioned the training so obviously one of the objectives of.
Claire Standley (elle) : Oui, et lorsque vous parlez de la formation, sachant évidemment que l'un des objectifs de
Claire Standley (she/her): This interview is that we're helping to provide more training materials so you are contributing hopefully to expanding the availability of of training resources for IMS across the world.
Claire Standley (elle) : cette interview a pour but d'aider à fournir plus de matériel de formation, j'espère que vous contribuez à étendre la disponibilité des ressources de formation pour l'IMS à travers le monde.
Claire Standley (she/her): And you mentioned the district so that's a great jumping point, I think, could you speak a little bit to your experience of implementing IMS at the sub national level and how that's gone.
Claire Standley (elle) : Et vous avez mentionné le district, c'est donc un excellent point de départ, je pense. Pourriez-vous nous parler un peu de votre expérience de la mise en œuvre de l'IMS au niveau infranational et de la façon dont cela s'est passé ?
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Right, yes, before I answer that let me just say you're quite right in terms of you know, conducting training to make sure that we popularized this system, and you know very.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Oui, avant de répondre à cette question, permettez-moi de dire que vous avez tout à fait raison en ce qui concerne la formation pour s'assurer que nous popularisons ce système. Et
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Large large scale.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : à très grande échelle,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: And you know performing also training for the leadership is very important let's not forget that, because.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : la formation des dirigeants est très importante, ne l'oublions pas, car
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: They are the one that we want to seek them by in if they don't they're not convinced they they will not be willing to support the activities so that's why.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : ce sont eux que nous recherchons. S'ils ne sont pas convaincus, ils ne seront pas prêts à soutenir les activités. C'est pour cela,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: First of all, I mean we need to include in our training program the leadership executive training for public health emergency management, including principles of EOC.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : tout d'abord, que nous devons inclure dans notre programme de formation, la formation des cadres pour la gestion des urgences en santé publique, y compris les principes du EOC,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: operations and also the use of IMS and also the the the importance of the IMS and I think this was proven in my experience, I mean the the importance of the the IMS when we tried to implement this at the district level, and you are quite right in asking that question, I can.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : les opérations et aussi l'utilisation de l'IMS ainsi que l'importance de l'IMS. Je pense que cela a été prouvé, par mon expérience, l'importance de l'IMS lors de la mise en œuvre de ce système au niveau du district. Et vous avez tout à fait raison de poser cette question, je peux
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Remember that during the measles outbreak in Guinea in 2027, 2017.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : me rappeler que pendant l'épidémie de rougeole en Guinée en 2017,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: I think that was just after we had.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : je pense que c'était juste après que nous soyons
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: come out of a long battle against.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : sortis d'une longue bataille contre
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: EVD, Ebola virus disease outbreak, and we we actually were facing issues in terms of managing effectively the measles outbreak, because many districts were having sporadic cases of measles.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : l'EVD, l'épidémie de la maladie du virus Ebola, nous étions alors confrontés à des problèmes de gestion efficace de l'épidémie de rougeole, car de nombreux districts présentaient des cas sporadiques de rougeole.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: And so, at one point in time, the Ministry of Health declared the emergency which was on the eighth of February, if my memory is not failing.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Et ainsi, à un moment donné, le ministère de la Santé a déclaré l'urgence, le 8 février, si ma mémoire n'est pas défaillante,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: 2017 and so following that we said okay Why not use this opportunity to show the goods of the IMS use.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : en 2017 et donc à la suite de cela nous avons décidé d'utiliser cette opportunité pour montrer les biens de l'utilisation de l'IMS.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: So that maybe the leadership will accept the principles of the EOC so we actually staged an EOC at the sub national level in Conakry, Conakry is the capital city of Guinea and.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Pour que les dirigeants acceptent les principes de l'EOC, nous avons donc organisé une EOC au niveau sous-national à Conakry, la capitale de la Guinée.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: The direction de la sante de la ville de Conakry, which is a regional level, so the entity, where we actually had to pull in you know staff from the EOC including trained.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : La direction de la santé de la ville de Conakry, qui est un niveau régional, donc l'entité, où nous avons dû faire appel au personnel de l'EOC, y compris
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: a trained fellow from the US CDC to activate the IMS system, so all the functions were activated, including the liaison officer, the.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : une personne formée par le CDC américain pour activer le système IMS. Donc toutes les fonctions ont été activées, y compris l'officier de liaison,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Communication officer, which is just an adaptation from the public information officer and also the security officer and then we had also this operational section, like the.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : le responsable de la communication, c'est-à-dire une adaptation du responsable de l'information publique, ainsi que le responsable de la sécurité. Et puis nous avions aussi cette section opérationnelle. Comme
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Operation section chief we had a logistics chief and also implemented a activated the the planning section, and also the.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : le chef de la section opérationnelle, nous avions un chef de la logistique et nous avons également mis en place une section de planification, et
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Human resources, financial administration so basically as a result of this, some of the benefit, I will not go into details, there's a very total report I may share with you later, but some of the benefit of this was.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : les ressources humaines, l'administration financière. Je n'entrerai pas dans les détails, il y a un rapport très complet que je pourrais partager avec vous plus tard, mais certains des avantages de ceci étaient,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: I w ill single out for example, the fact that previously during the mass campaign of vaccinations
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : par exemple, le fait qu'auparavant, pendant la campagne de vaccination de masse,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: people had to wait till very late in the afternoon, sometimes they could stay up until 9pm to wait for reports from the field and then be able to.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : les personnes devaient attendre jusqu'à très tard dans l'après-midi, et parfois jusqu'à 21 heures pour recevoir les rapports de terrain afin
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: start now thinking about how to address some of the gaps or issues that have been identified in the field, yet, with the implementation of the IMS.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : de commencer tout de suite à réfléchir sur la manière de combler certaines des lacunes ou des problèmes identifiés sur le terrain, jusqu'à présent, avec la mise en œuvre de l'IMS.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: What was happening, all issues were reported in real time and also address, and then, if they could not be addressed at the EOC that was staged at the DDSCO
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Tous les problèmes étaient signalés en temps réel et également traités, et ensuite, s'ils ne pouvaient pas être traités à l'EOC qui était organisé à la DDSCO,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: There were escalated to the leadership level to find solution so which resulted really in a very positive outcome, as you know, the even we saw some kind of improvement in terms of the.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : ils étaient alors remontés au niveau de la direction pour trouver une solution. Ceci a eu un résultat très positif, comme vous le savez, nous avons même vu une sorte d'amélioration en termes
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: The vaccination coverage, so the IMS was then  a huge success at the time, and as a result, the Director of the the ANSS in Guinea actually said okay we're going to.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : de couverture vaccinale, donc l'IMS a été un énorme succès à l'époque. En conséquence, le directeur de l'ANSS en Guinée a donné son OK
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: set EOCs at all districts to be able to help the management of outbreak. So yes, and I think you know identity is really have have been actually seen throughout the implementation of the.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : pour mettre en place des EOC dans tous les districts afin d'aider à la gestion de l'épidémie. Donc oui, et je pense que vous savez que l'identité est réellement observée tout au long de la mise en œuvre de
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: The the the EOC, the IMS at the DDSCO.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : l'EOC, l'IMS dans la DDSCO.
Claire Standley (she/her): Fantastic and, just to clarify for our listeners the aisense is the national health security agency and getting which was established during the Ebola response actually in has now become the lead.
Claire Standley (elle) : Fantastique. Afin de clarifier pour nos auditeurs, l'ANSS est l'agence nationale de sécurité sanitaire qui a été créée pendant la réponse au virus Ebola et qui est maintenant devenue le chef de
Claire Standley (she/her): Implementing agency for all health security and International Health Regulations related activities.
Claire Standley (elle) : la mise en œuvre d'une agence pour toutes les activités liées à la sécurité sanitaire et au Règlement sanitaire international.
Claire Standley (she/her): yeah, so I think just you know i'm really interested by by the description of how positive the lessons.
Claire Standley (elle) : Oui, je suis donc très intéressée par la description positive de ces leçons,
Claire Standley (she/her): How positive an experience it was at the sub national level in terms of improving coordination and response and and I think it also highlights nicely, the idea that.
Claire Standley (elle) : à quel point l'expérience a été bénéfique au niveau sous-national en termes d'amélioration de la coordination et de la réponse. Et je pense que ceci souligne bien l'idée que
Claire Standley (she/her): EOCs and particularly the IMS structure can be used, of course, for outbreak response but also potentially in the future for mass vaccination campaigns in a more routine way, so I think that's something really positive to take from this.
Claire Standley (elle) : les EOC et en particulier la structure IMS peuvent être utilisés, bien sûr, pour la réponse aux épidémies mais aussi potentiellement à l'avenir pour les campagnes de vaccination de masse de manière plus routinière, donc je pense que c'est un point très positif à retenir.
Claire Standley (she/her): And, are there any final lessons learned that you'd share from from either your national level or your your sub national level experience of implementing IMS.
Claire Standley (elle) : Et, y a-t-il des enseignements finaux que vous voudriez partager avec nous à partir de votre expérience de mise en œuvre de l'IMS, que ce soit au niveau national ou infranational ?
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Yes.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Oui.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: What I can see is that.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Je constate que
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: You know, when you take the IHR core capacities, I mean the IHR.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : quand vous prenez les capacités essentielles du IHR, c'est-à-dire
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: International Health Regulations
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : le règlement sanitaire international,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: They enjoin Member member countries actually to develop this capacity to be able to to prevent, detect and respond to an emergency or national or international concern.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : les pays membres se rejoignent dans le développement de cette capacité afin d'être en mesure de prévenir, détecter et répondre à une urgence ou à une préoccupation nationale ou internationale.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: So really all countries should really engage in building those capacity to be able to prepare for to prevent from respond to.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Donc, tous les pays devraient réellement s'engager dans le développement de ces capacités afin de pouvoir se préparer, prévenir, répondre
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: And also mitigate the risk or effect of public health emergency of national or international concern so as part of the preparation, really.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : et aussi atténuer le risque ou l'effet d'une urgence de santé publique de portée nationale ou internationale. Donc dans le cadre de la préparation,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: We have to develop these tools and ensure that we train staff so when the IMS was have been implemented in Guinea and that the beneficial was shown not only.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : nous devions développer ces outils et nous assurer de former le personnel. Ainsi lorsque l'IMS a été mis en œuvre en Guinée et que les avantages ont été démontrés,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Throughout the response to Ebola but also when we moved into responding to measles we implemented the IMS at the.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : tout au long de la réponse à l'Ebola, mais aussi lors de la réponse à la rougeole, nous avons mis en œuvre l'IMS
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: DDSCO because some of these benefit that we're seeing actually was an incentive is it actually was a driving force behind the.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : au DDSCO, car certains des avantages que nous constations étaient en réalité une incitation et une force motrice derrière
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Implementation of the IMS at the district level so with the support of partners, I would not want to cite any one of them so that, for fear of leaving some more out.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : la mise en œuvre de l'IMS au niveau du district, donc avec le soutien des partenaires. Je ne les citerai pas, de peur d'en oublier d'autres.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: But definitely we created the EOC with the IMS function at the district level and what we have seen is.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Il est certain que nous avons créé l'EOC avec la fonction IMS au niveau du district et ce que nous avons observé,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: That, for example in terms of data collection in terms of reporting information from the field.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : par exemple en termes de collecte de données, en termes de rapport d'informations du terrain,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: And there is all the tools, the templates were developed and they get all given to the district, for example, the SitRep, the situational awareness, is a report on.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : que tous les outils sont présents, les modèles ont été développés et sont tous fournis au district. Par exemple, le SitRep, la connaissance de la situation, est un rapport.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: How basically the, the situation is being managed or being dealt with from the from the district level, so it also gives some kind of authority to the district and not allow you know the national level to always move whenever there is an emergency, so you are given some kind of.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Fondamentalement, la situation est gérée ou traitée à partir du niveau du district, donnant ainsi une certaine forme d'autorité au district et permettant au niveau national de ne pas toujours devoir se déplacer. Donc une certaine forme
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: authority and also some kind of autonomy to the district, to be the first responders and to be able to manage and then only request assistance from the national level when they are overwhelmed and we have seen this and really I think there was a resurgence of.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : d'autorité et aussi d'autonomie est donnée au district, pour qu'il soit le premier intervenant et qu'il soit capable de gérer et ensuite de demander de l'aide au niveau national uniquement lorsqu'il est débordé. Je pense tout particulièrement à la réapparition de
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: EVD in Guinea in 2020.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : l'EVD en Guinée en 2020.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Basically, in February and also recently a Marburg case also was detected in the Forest Region, and the districts actually used some of these principles, and they were going to.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : En février et aussi récemment un cas de Marburg a été détecté dans la région forestière, et les districts ont utilisé certains de ces principes, et ils ont
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: carry out this coordination meeting and also use the SitReps fill them and send them to the national level and which actually alleviate the burden of the national level activity, because if you were to have in a large massive.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : organisé cette réunion de coordination et ont également utilisé les SitRep pour les remplir et les envoyer au niveau national, permettant ainsi d'alléger la charge de l'activité au niveau national. Ceci, car si vous deviez avoir une épidémie massive,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: outbreak, if you were to actually collate, all the the the field data.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : si vous deviez collecter toutes les données de terrain,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: It will be wouldn't become really, really, really tedious so the fact that they are able to fill this information in an international level, we can only.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : ceci deviendrait très fastidieux. Donc le fait qu'ils soient capables de remplir ces informations à un niveau international, nous pouvons alors seulement
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Trying to do a summary report that we can share with stakeholders and the leadership and also some of these supporting partners.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : tenter de faire un rapport de synthèse que nous pouvons partager avec les parties prenantes et les dirigeants, ainsi que certains de ces partenaires de soutien.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: And that was really a very, very good, positive outcome, so, in a nutshell, I think the IMS has been a good experience in Guinea and as a result, I think.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Et ceci a donné un résultat très positif, donc, en bref, je pense que l'IMS a été une excellente expérience en Guinée.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: As a result, of developing the tools and of these plans, some of the neighbors actually also always use the example of Guinea to implement the IMS structure in their country, one of them, I can think of is Mali.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Et au résultat, grâce au développement des outils et de ces plans, certains de nos voisins ont toujours utilisé l'exemple de la Guinée pour mettre en place la structure IMS dans leur pays, je pense notamment au Mali.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: What I have my colleagues who have also said they want to actually you know implement the IMS and the EOC principles in their country, the same way it has been in Guinea.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Mes collègues ont également déclaré vouloir mettre en œuvre les principes de l'IMS et de l'EOC dans leur pays, comme cela a été le cas en Guinée.
Claire Standley (she/her): Fantastic Thank you so much, and, of course, you know that mentioning relieving pressure on a national level was especially important with COVID-19 happening in the background right, so the.
Claire Standley (elle) : Fantastique. Merci beaucoup, et, bien sûr, vous savez que le fait de mentionner la réduction de la pression au niveau national était particulièrement important avec le COVID-19 qui se déroule en arrière-plan, donc
Claire Standley (she/her): National EOC was, of course, very busy dealing with the pandemic and national level implementation of control measures and so.
Claire Standley (elle) : le EOC national était, bien sûr, très occupé à gérer la pandémie et la mise en œuvre des mesures de contrôle au niveau national.
Claire Standley (she/her): It was even more important that the districts were able to take charge and manage successfully those.
Claire Standley (elle) : Il était donc encore plus crucial que les districts soient en mesure de prendre les choses en main et de gérer
Claire Standley (she/her): resurgence of Ebola that you mentioned, and of course the Marburg case so again showing how it's important, especially when there's limited resources human or financial to have that hierarchy of management right.
Claire Standley (elle) : la résurgence de l'Ebola que vous avez mentionnée, et bien sûr le cas de Marburg. Ceci montre à nouveau qu'il est important, surtout lorsque les ressources humaines ou financières sont limitées, de disposer d'une bonne hiérarchie de gestion.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: yeah and also maybe i'm forgetting one single point, maybe that can be also seen as a success.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Oui, et peut-être que j'oublie un seul point, qui peut être aussi considéré comme un succès,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Because you know they are.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : parce que vous savez qu'ils le sont.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Emergency Management entities that have been developed following the installation of the EOC and the IMS principles in the district, I mean those are the epidemic treatment centers were built in the district.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Les entités de gestion des urgences ont été développées suite à l'installation de l'EOC et des principes IMS dans le district, c'est-à-dire des centres de traitement des épidémies qui ont été construits dans le district,
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: to monitor case management, for all these epidemic disease when from when they occur, and also, we had a district level of the EPARE, they are called EPARE, this is a rapid response team, EPARE is equipe
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : afin de surveiller la gestion des cas, pour toutes ces maladies épidémiques quand elles se produisent. Nous avons également obtenu un niveau de district de l'EPARE, c'est-à-dire une équipe de réponse rapide. L'EPARE signifie l'équipe
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: national d'alerte et de riposte in French, so the at the time the rapid response team was just developed at the national level, with the support of Expertise France, but when actually we.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : nationale d'alerte et de riposte en français. À l'époque, l'équipe de réponse rapide était seulement développée au niveau national, avec le soutien d'Expertise France. Cependant lorsque
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: implemented an EOC with the IMS principle on the team, the district, it was so much of a success that it led way to the.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : nous avons mis en place un EOC avec le principe IMS sur l'équipe, le district, ceci a été un tel succès que cela a conduit à
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: installation of the rapid response team in the district, and so you see now that coordination is happening there, under the leadership of the district and.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : l'installation de l'équipe de réponse rapide dans le district. Vous constatez maintenant que la coordination se passe là, sous la direction du district et de
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Their health district head, and whenever it is an outbreak there's a meeting and following the meeting.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : leur chef de district sanitaire. Et chaque fois qu'une épidémie se produit, il y a une réunion, suivi d'une autre réunion.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: The RRTs are dispatched to go and do investigations and produce reports in real time, and share them in in a relatively very short time. Before what used to happen, we used to always send a team from the national level, one to the the.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Les RRT sont envoyées pour faire des enquêtes et produire des rapports en temps réel, et les partager dans un délai relativement court. Avant, ce qui se passait, c'est que nous envoyions toujours une équipe du niveau national, une pour
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: The investigation and so some of these.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : l'enquête et donc certaines de
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Lessons need to be really shared to so how good and effective the IMS can be in terms of coordinating and communicating throughout the management of break.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : ces leçons doivent être absolument partagées pour montrer à quel point l'IMS peut être performant et efficace en termes de coordination et de communication tout au long de la gestion de la rupture.
Claire Standley (she/her): Well, thank you again Amadou that that's really helpful information, I think, and again lots of great lessons learned from from getting his experience over the last several years and.
Claire Standley (elle) : Eh bien, merci encore à Amadou pour ces informations très utiles et ces nombreuses grandes leçons à tirer de son expérience au cours des dernières années.
Claire Standley (she/her): With great credit to yourself and your colleagues who played such a leading role in supporting the development of those capacities, so thank you very much again.
Claire Standley (elle) : Avec un grand mérite pour vous et vos collègues qui ont joué un rôle de premier plan dans le soutien au développement de ces capacités, donc encore un grand merci.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore: Thank you, my pleasure.
Sierra Leone Dr Amadou Traore : Merci, c'était un plaisir.